Guide to the Jack O'Brien Papers AIA.067
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VII: Jack O'Brien - Personal Materials, 1879-2020 (inclusive), 1971-2017 (bulk); 3.69 Linear Feet in 9 legal size manuscript boxes, 17 folders in an additional legal size manuscript box, 1 folder in an oversize box, 2 artifacts in a card box, 4 audio visual discs in a media box, 1 poster in
  This series contains personal materials related to Jack O'Brien and focuses on subjects like O'Brien's family history, his interest in Irish culture, as well as his support of Irish cultural organizations and institutions.
  Materials include correspondence, St. Patrick's Day Parade magazines, Jack O'Briens 2015 St. Patrick's Day Parade Grand Marshal magnet, Irish Heritage Festival magazines and flyers, brochures, papers belonging to Irish American organizations, programs, booklets, DVDs, newspaper clippings, emails, photographs, posters, stickers, vinyl records, business cards, buttons, and newsletters.
  - The 29th Nation's Capital Feis All American Championship, 2016 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - The 106th Congress and Holocaust Related Legislation, 2000; cuid42467 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - 1916-2016 Centennial Committee - An Initiative of Clan na Gael and Irish Northern Aid, cuid42565 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Acquisition of Irish Citizenship, 1991-1992, 2010; cuid42468 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Albert E. Casey Collection (Irish Materials), 1983; cuid42469 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - The American Ireland Fund 5th National Gala Program, 1997; cuid42470 (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - American Irish Bicentennial Committee Magazine, 1976; cuid42471 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - An Appeal from Ireland to America, undated; cuid42472 (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - Annapolis Irish Rowing Club, 2019; cuid42473 (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - Aras Ui Chonghaile, 2019; cuid42474 (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - Archbishop Edwin F. O'Brien, undated; cuid42475 (Box 47, Folder 24)
  - Armagh Gaelic Football Club of New York Program, 2012; cuid42476 (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - "Butcher's Dozen: A Lesson for the Octave Widgery", undated; cuid42477 (Box 47, Folder 26)
  - Bundornan, County Donegal, Ireland, 2012; cuid42478 (Box 47, Folder 27)
  - Business Cards, undated; cuid42479 (Box 47, Folder 28)
  - Buttons, undated; cuid42480 (Box 47, Folder 29, Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Buttons List, undated; cuid42481 (Box 47, Folder 30)
  - Calendars, 2007, 2010, 2016-2017, 2018-2019; cuid42482 (Box 47, Folder 31, Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Capital City Hibernian News, 2002-2003; cuid42483 (Box 47, Folder 32)
  - Cartoons, undated; cuid42484 (Box 47, Folder 33)
  - Catholic Historical Society of Washington Newsletter, 2003-2004; cuid42485 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Celebrating Our Heritage (AARP), 1992; cuid42486 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Celebrating the Artful Life of Maria Mooney, 2013; cuid42487 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Celtic Calendar, 1996; cuid42488 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Celtic Directory, 2003, 2005; cuid42489 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Celtic Monthly (Irish American Magazine), 1879; cuid42490 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Celtic News Service, 2004; cuid42491 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Center for Irish Studies - Catholic University, 2016; cuid42566 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Columbia Typographical Union, 1965, 1995, 2005; cuid42492 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - "Commemorations and Things Worth Remembering", 2016; cuid42493 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Connolly Books, 1985; cuid42494 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Conway Mill Trust, 2010-2011, 2018-2019; cuid42495 (Box 48, Folder 11, Box 64, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1979-2017; cuid42496 (Box 48, Folder 12-13)
  - Day in the Bog '95, 1995; cuid42497 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Discussion with NYU to digitize Irish People newspapers, 2013; cuid42498 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Edmond of the Hill: A Noble Hero and Wonderful Song, 2012; cuid42499 (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Emails, 2006, 2009, 2011-2020; cuid42500 (Box 49, Folder 1, Box 65)
  - The Emerald Isle Club, 1974, 1996-1997; cuid42501 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Father Daniel Berrigan, 2016; cuid42567 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Flyers and Brochures, 1975, 1986-2002, 2009-2015; cuid42502 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Gaels Newsletter, 2003, 2005; cuid42503 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - The Gaelic League/Conrodh Na Gaeilge, 1981-1983; cuid42504 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - George Washington Park Custis and the Young Ireland Movement, 1958; cuid42505 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - The Green Pages, undated; cuid42506 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Green Ireland "Erin Go Bragh" Flag, undated; cuid42564 (Box Shared Tamiment 081, Folder 11)
  - The Guerin Project - Reconstruction of the GAA Field Templemore, Tipperary, 2004; cuid42507 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - The Harp: The Voice of the Irish Impression, 1991; cuid42508 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - The Hedgemaster, 1999, 2004-2012; cuid42509 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - The Hibernian magazine, 2008; cuid42510 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Holy Cross - Centenary Pilgrimage, 2003; cuid42511 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Invitations, 1990, 2017, 2019; cuid42512 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Ireland Magazines, 1972, 1991-1992, 2001, 2008, 2010; cuid42513 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Irish American Club, 1992-1994; cuid42514 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Irish American Cultural Institute, 1986, 1989-1991, 1995-1996, 2001-2003, 2008; cuid42515 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Irish American Heritage Month, 1992-2018; cuid42516 (Box 50, Folder 4, Box 57, Folder 16, Box 61)
  - Irish American Heritage Museum, 1991, 2013-2014; cuid42517 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Irish American Heritage Museum Newsletter, 2008; cuid42570 (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Irish American Heritage Museum Trivet, undated; cuid42518 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - The Irish American Museum of Washington, DC, undated; cuid42519 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Irish American Peace Award, 2011; cuid42520 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Irish Apostolate USA, 2012; cuid42521 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Irish Arts Review, 1984-1985; cuid42522 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - An Irish Blessing, undated; cuid42523 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Irish Cemetaries, 2002; cuid42524 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Ireland 100: Celebrating a Century of Irish Arts & Culture, undated; cuid42568 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Ireland 2016 Centenary Programme in the United States of America, cuid42569 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Ireland Chamber of Commerce in the United States, 1993; cuid42525 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Irish Cultural Societies, 1975-1980, 1988-1989, 2002-2003; cuid42526 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Irish Diaspora Center, 2019; cuid42527 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - "Irish Disclaimers", undated; cuid42528 (Box Shared Tamiment 088, Audio 067.0008)
  - The Irish Exile, 1920; cuid42529 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Irish Festival, 1975-2019; cuid42530 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Irish Festival Magazines, 1986, 1997, 2006-2008, 2013; cuid42531 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Irish Folk Festival Magazines, 1988-1995; cuid42532 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Irish Heritage Festival, 1994-2018; cuid42533 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Irish Immigrant Outreach, undated; cuid42534 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - The Irish Immigration Center, 2010; cuid42535 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Irish Language Act, 2017; cuid42536 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Irish Lobby for Immigration Reform Dinner Dance, 2007; cuid42537 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Irish Music Magazine, 2019; cuid42538 (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Irish Railroad Workers Museum, 2009, 2015-2020; cuid42539 (Box 52, Folder 1, Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Irish Republican History Musem, undated; cuid42540 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Irish War Veterans, undated; cuid42541 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Jack O'Brien St. Patrick's Day Parade Grand Marshal, 2015; cuid42542 (Box 52, Folder 4, Box Shared Tamiment 081, Folder 12)
  - Kennedy for President - Election Pamphlet, circa 1960; cuid42571 (Box 65, Folder 17)
  - The Kings of the Kilburn High Road (Play Program), undated; cuid42543 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - La Dearg, 2017; cuid42544 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Landscapes of a Friendship, undated; cuid42545 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Le Eithne (Irish Naval Service), undated; cuid42546 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Leather pouch, undated; cuid42547 (Box 59)
  - "Lincoln and the Irish", 2019; cuid42548 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Linenhall Library (Belfast), 1994-2004; cuid42549 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - The Linnet: The Irish World Past and Present, 1991; cuid42550 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Martin Lyons, 2020; cuid42551 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Michael J. O'Brien (Ancestor of Jack O'Brien), 1915, 2006-2007; cuid42552 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Michael J. Redding and Irish American Patriotism, undated; cuid42553 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Military Images Magazine, 1990; cuid42554 (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - National Graves Association, 1986, 2014, 2018; cuid42555 (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - National History Day Irish Award, undated; cuid42556 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - National Museum of the American People (Proposal), undated; cuid42557 (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Newsletter of Irish Activities of Maryland, 1997; cuid42558 (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper - Orange Standard, 2007-2008; cuid42559 (Box 52, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1973, 1984, 2004, 2014-2019; cuid42560 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - O'Brien Family, 1926, 1930, 1996, 2002, 2011-2019; cuid42561 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Oatland's Celtic Festival, 1996; cuid42562 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Ode to Young Ireland, 1842; cuid42563 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - "Patrick MacGuire, Revolutionary and Gaelic Footballer", 2016 (Box 53)
  - Petticoat Rebels, undated; cuid42462 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_16)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Policy Proposal for the Irish Overseas and Diaspora, undated (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Postcards, 1975-1977, 1980, 1991 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Professor William Casey, 2008-2011 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Provie Lullaby Record, 1973 (Box Shared Tamiment 037, Sound disc--vinyl 067.0013)
  - The Raparees, 1971 (Box Shared Tamiment 037, Sound disc--vinyl 067.0012)
  - Rebel Risin', 2013; cuid42459 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_10)
  - The Revolution Papers, 2016-2017 (Box 53, Folder 10-11)
  - Rhode Island Police Officers Emerald Society Inc, 1997 (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Rose of Tralee, 2009-2012 (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Tara Hill - Roll on the Day, 1993 (Box Shared Tamiment 084, Audiocassette 067.0005)
  - The Saint Mary's Moorings, 2013 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - "Senator for the Irish Disapora", 2017-2018 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - September 11, 2001, 2001-2002 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - The Shannon Tide, 1981 (Box Shared Tamiment 037, Sound disc--vinyl 067.0009)
  - Smithsonian Museum Controversy, 2007 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Songs and Recitations of Ireland, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Speech - Custis Lee Mansion on St. Patrick's Day, 1963 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - St. Brendan's Cup, 1984 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - St. Patrick's Centre, undated (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - St. Patrick's Day, 1987-2017 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - St. Patrick's Day - History of the Philadelphia St. Patrick's Day Parade, undated; cuid42460 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_4)
  - St. Patrick's Day Magazine, 1987-2019 (Box 54, Folder 10-11, Box 55, Folder 1-5, Box 56, Folder 1-2, Box 65, Folder 28)
  - Step About: Slip Jigs, Reels, Set Dances, 1969 (Box Shared Tamiment 037, Sound disc--vinyl 067.0011)
  - Stickers, undated (Box 56, Folder 3, Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Treoir Magazine, 1995 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Wage Agreement, 2002 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Washington Arsenal Explosion: Sesquicentennial Dedication, 2014 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Washington Ireland Program, 2016 (Box 65, Folder 29)
  - "We the People 200 Parade", 1987 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - "What the Irish Have Said" Knowledge Cards, undated (Box 59)
  - When I Go Back to Ireland, 2013; cuid42461 (Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_AIA_067_ER_9)
  - The Wicklow Boy, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 037, Sound disc--vinyl 067.0010)
  - WNTV-53 (Northern Virgina Public TV), 1991 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - World Peace Prize Awarding Council (Irish National Caucus), undated (Box 65, Folder 30)